<idea-plugin url="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes">
    <id>com.codebasenotes.jetbrains</id>
    <name>Codebase Notes</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes">Codebase Notes</vendor>
    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>Shared, Git-versioned notes for your codebase structure — across JetBrains IDEs, VS Code, and TRAE.</b></p>

        <p>
            Put explanations such as “why this directory exists”, “where the project core is”, and
            “where new features plug in” directly beside files and directories in the Project view —
            instead of losing them in chat history, personal notes, or outdated documentation.
        </p>

        <p>
            Codebase Notes stores all notes in a repository-local <code>.codebase-notes.json</code> file.
            Commit it to Git so teammates and users of other supported editors can share the same context.
        </p>

        <h3>What it helps with</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Onboarding: mark the core order flow or the main application entry.</li>
            <li>Architecture: identify public API boundaries and important modules.</li>
            <li>Maintenance: explain generated files and paths that should not be edited manually.</li>
            <li>Navigation: mark stable sources of truth and extension points.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Core features</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Edit, style, or remove notes from the Project view context menu.</li>
            <li>Display short notes directly beside files and directories.</li>
            <li>Use six semantic colors to turn the project tree into a code map.</li>
            <li>Keep note paths in sync when files or directories are renamed or moved.</li>
            <li>Share one open JSON format with VS Code and TRAE.</li>
            <li>English and Simplified Chinese UI that follows the IDE language.</li>
            <li>No account, cloud service, telemetry, or proprietary database.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Six code-map styles</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Core (red):</b> the project backbone — learn this first.</li>
            <li><b>Focus (yellow):</b> easy-to-miss relationships, constraints, or details.</li>
            <li><b>Important (blue):</b> important modules and engineering entry points.</li>
            <li><b>Stable (green):</b> trusted sources of truth and reliable baselines.</li>
            <li><b>Extension (purple):</b> places where new capabilities plug in.</li>
            <li><b>Default (gray):</b> ordinary responsibility descriptions.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
            Colors describe code structure rather than errors or runtime status:
            red for the backbone, yellow for details, blue for importance,
            green for trusted baselines, and purple for extension points.
        </p>

        <h3>Getting started</h3>
        <ol>
            <li>Open a project in a supported JetBrains IDE.</li>
            <li>Right-click a file or directory in the Project view.</li>
            <li>Choose <b>Codebase Notes → Edit Text Note</b>.</li>
            <li>Commit <code>.codebase-notes.json</code> to Git if the note should be shared.</li>
        </ol>

        <p>
            Default shortcuts: <code>Option+R</code> on macOS or <code>Alt+R</code> on Windows/Linux
            to edit text; <code>Shift+Option+R</code> or <code>Shift+Alt+R</code> to set a style.
        </p>

        <h3>Data and privacy</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Notes stay inside the opened project.</li>
            <li>Writes use locking, temporary files, and conflict detection to avoid silent overwrites.</li>
            <li>The JSON format is validated by a shared schema and cross-language conformance tests.</li>
            <li>The plugin does not collect or transmit project data.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
            <a href="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes">Source code and documentation</a>
            · <a href="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes/issues">Report an issue or request a feature</a>
            · <a href="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes/releases/latest">Latest release</a>
        </p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>0.1.24</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Unified JetBrains, VS Code, and TRAE around six code-map styles: Default, Important, Focus, Core, Stable, and Extension.</li>
            <li>Added a shared color model for identifying the project backbone, details, important modules, trusted baselines, and extension points.</li>
            <li>Added an AI initialization guide for generating concise project notes with consistent semantics.</li>
            <li>Removed a Kotlin-generated deprecated API compatibility bridge reported by Marketplace validation.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/joeljhou/codebase-notes/releases">Full release history</a></p>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <resource-bundle>messages.CodebaseNotesBundle</resource-bundle>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <projectService serviceImplementation="com.codebasenotes.jetbrains.CodebaseNotesProjectService"/>
        <projectViewNodeDecorator implementation="com.codebasenotes.jetbrains.ProjectViewNoteDecorator"/>
        <notificationGroup id="Codebase Notes" displayType="BALLOON"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <group id="CodebaseNotes.Group" popup="true">
            <action
                id="CodebaseNotes.EditNote"
                class="com.codebasenotes.jetbrains.EditNoteAction">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt R"/>
            </action>
            <action
                id="CodebaseNotes.SetNoteStyle"
                class="com.codebasenotes.jetbrains.SetNoteStyleAction">
                <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="shift alt R"/>
            </action>
            <separator/>
            <action
                id="CodebaseNotes.RemoveNote"
                class="com.codebasenotes.jetbrains.RemoveNoteAction"/>
            <add-to-group
                group-id="ProjectViewPopupMenu"
                anchor="after"
                relative-to-action="ProjectViewEditSource"/>
        </group>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
